<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aaron Dancer&#39;s Blog</title>
    <atom:link href="http://aarondancer.com/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <link>http://aarondancer.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Official blog of Aaron Dancer. Software engineer, UX Researcher, and Event Organizer. Mainly programming and UX related blog posts, with some posting about events, life events, company, and community. 
</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 17:13:54 -0500</pubDate>
    
      <item>
        <title>Accessing Environment Variables on an Azure Web App in PHP</title>
        <link>http://aarondancer.com/blog/2015/04/30/accessing-environment-variables-on-an-azure-web-app-in-php.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://aarondancer.com/blog/2015/04/30/accessing-environment-variables-on-an-azure-web-app-in-php.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TLDR;&lt;/strong&gt; If you want to access environment variables set on your Azure Web App in PHP, use &lt;code&gt;getenv()&lt;/code&gt;. Example below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$api_key = getenv(&#39;ENVVARNAME&#39;);&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While working on the contact form for my &lt;a href=&quot;http://aarondancer.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;personal website&lt;/a&gt;, I ran into issues with accessing environment variables I had set in my Azure Web App.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When building my contact form I decided to use SendGrid to power it (which I purchased from the Azure Marketplace). In order to use the SendGrid API I needed to include the API keys and login credentials. It&#39;s very bad practice to include these keys in your source code (especially when open source like my website), so I added some environment variables in the configuration section of my Azure Web App.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/R3fCoig.png&quot; alt=&quot;Azure Web App Environment Variable Configuration&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since these variables are set for the whole app, I figured they were global. So I tried accessing them like so: &lt;code&gt;$_ENV[&quot;SGUSER&quot;]&lt;/code&gt;. However, after much testing I found that accessing them with &lt;code&gt;$_ENV&lt;/code&gt; would yield nothing. I tested with &lt;code&gt;$_SERVER&lt;/code&gt; as well with the same result. So, after a bit of searching on Bing I found the &lt;a href=&quot;http://php.net/manual/en/function.getenv.php&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;getenv()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; function. This seemed to do the trick!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 21:17:23 -0500</pubDate>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
